Inventory of the James Robert Huntley papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Speeches and writings
  - Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development (OECD)/Group of Four, 1971 June-September (Box-folder 13: 8)
  - "Internationale Zusammenarbeit zum Schutz der Umwelt" Munich lecture ("International Cooperation to Protect the Environment"), 1971 January (Box-folder 13: 9)
  - Pollution presentation for MCE, 1971 September (Box-folder 13: 10)
  - Rungstedgaard Conference, "Approaches to Learning About Collective Security and Conflict,", 1971 October-November (Box-folder 13: 11)
  - Europe-America Conference
    - Resolutions, news releases, and delegates, 1973 March (Box-folder 13: 12)
    - Speeches, 1973 March (Box-folder 13: 13-15)
    - Correspondence, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 13: 16)
- Battelle Seminar and Study Program/Advanced International Systems
  - Mutual Images/Japan and West, book, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 13: 17)
  - Atlantic-Pacific Bibliography, book, 1976-1982 (Box-folder 13: 18)
- Personal correspondence, 1966-1969 (Box-folder 14: 1)
- College Federaliste d'Aoste, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 14: 2)
- Alexander Marc/Centre International de Formation Européenne (CIFE) correspondence and information, 1968-1974 (Box-folder 14: 3)
- Plans for an international university at Nice, 1969 June (Box-folder 14: 4)
- "The European Challenge to America," Berlin speech, 1969 October-November (Box-folder 14: 5)
- Atlantic Information Centre for Teachers, International Seminar for Teachers, 1969 November (Box-folder 14: 6)
- College of Europe, 1969-1973 (Box-folder 14: 7)
- Institut Européen des Hautes Etudes Internationales, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 14: 8)
- Centre International de Formation Européenne, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 14: 9)
- Centre Européen De Recherche en Sciences Sociales, 1970 February-March (Box-folder 14: 10)
- IBM management, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 14: 11)
- Speeches and lectures, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 14: 12)
- Personal correspondence, 1970-1973 (Box-folder 14: 13)
- Conference on Scientific and Cultural Exchange and European Cooperation, 1971 June (Box-folder 14: 14)
- "The Communications Gap,", 1971-1972 (Box-folder 14: 15)
- Correspondents world wide, 1972 September (Box-folder 14: 16)
- World Environment newsletter, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 14: 17)
- ESSO Lectures, 1973 October-November (Box-folder 14: 18)
- Wilton Park Conference, 1973 December (Box-folder 14: 19)
  Includes photograph.
- Europe 2000: Project 1 - Education, 1969 July (Box-folder 15: 1)
  Bound research proposal.
- Europe 2000: Project 3 - Urbanization, 1971 February (Box-folder 15: 2)
- Correspondence, Ambassador Schmidt, 1971-1975 (Box-folder 15: 3)
- Correspondence, 1966-1971 (Box-folder 15: 4-7)
- Documents for education (documents pour l'enseignement), 1972-1973 (Box-folder 15: 8)
- Correspondence, 1972-1974 (Box-folder 15: 9-12)
- Atlantic Community Reports, 1961-1980 (Box-folder 16: 1)
- Atlantic Study, 1969 August (Box-folder 16: 2)
- Speeches and writings
  - Atlantic Council Book Study Group, drafts of introduction, 1968 July (Box-folder 16: 3)
  - Atlantic Council Book Study Group, correspondence, drafts, notes, 1968-1971 (Box-folder 16: 4)
  - Europe and America: The Next Ten Years, correspondence, reviews, and publicity notes, 1968-1970 (Box-folder 16: 5-11)
  - International Symposium, Tokyo, correspondence, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 17: 1)
  - International Symposium, Tokyo, notes and materials, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 17: 2)
  - Mutual Images/Japan and the West
    - Correspondence, 1974-1978 (Box-folder 17: 3)
    - Grant proposal, 1975 (Box-folder 17: 4)
    - Collected material, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 17: 5-6)
    - Drafts and outlines, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 17: 7)
    - Notes, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 17: 8)
- Extending the Atlantic System, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 17: 9-10)
- Japanese-West Relations, monograph, 1976 (Box-folder 17: 11-12)
- Mitsubishi Research Institute, Global Infrastructure Fund, 1977-1979 (Box-folder 17: 13)
- Trilateral Prospects/Gerard Smith Conference, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 18: 1-2)
- "New Nomenclature for the Extended Atlantic System,", 1975-1976 (Box-folder 18: 3)
- "Historic Origins of the Modern Atlantic System,", 1975-1976 (Box-folder 18: 4)
- Denver Research Institute Science and Technology Conference, 1976 (Box-folder 18: 5)
- International Executive Seminar Series, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 18: 6)
- "World Politics in the 1980s: A BASICS Report,", 1980 September (Box-folder 18: 7)
- International Community Building, attachments, 1981 April (Box-folder 18: 8)
- "World Politics in the 1980s," outlines and drafts, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 19: 1)
- "World Politics in the 1980s," tables and figures, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 19: 2)
- Correspondence, 1979 (Box-folder 19: 3-6)
- Correspondence, 1979 (Box-folder 20: 1-4)
- Battelle Seminar and Study Program correspondence book
  - 1975 (Box-folder 20: 5)
  - 1976 (Box-folder 21: 1)
  - 1977 (Box-folder 21: 2-3)
  - 1978 (Box-folder 22: 1-2)
  - 1979 January-June (Box-folder 22: 3)
- Battelle Seminar and Study Program James M. McDonald correspondence book
  - 1979 July-December (Box-folder 23: 1)
  - 1980 (Box-folder 23: 2)
  - 1981 (Box-folder 23: 3-4)
- Chronology of Committees for a Community of Democracies development and accomplishments, 1979-1989 (Box-folder 24: 1)
- Diaries
  - "Just Over the Next Ridge: A Memoir of the Cold War and Beyond," memoir of Huntley, 2004 July (Box-folder 24: 2)
    Contains CD-ROM.
  - Diary of James Robert Huntley: Volume 1, 1952-1976 (Box-folder 24: 3)
  - Diary of James Robert Huntley: Volume 2, 1976-2004 (Box-folder 24: 4)
  - Supplemental travel diary of James Robert Huntley, 1990-2004 (Box-folder 24: 5)
- The Trilateral Commission Vancouver Plenary Meeting, program, participants, and profiles, 1996 April (Box-folder 24: 6)
- The Trilateral Commission, working group papers, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 24: 7)
- Diaries
  - Supplemental Travel Diary of James Robert Huntley, 1990-2004 (Box-folder 24: 8)
- Battelle: "BASICS" procedures, 1979-1981 (Box-folder 25: 1)
- Trilateral Commission
  - Annual meeting, Vancouver, 1996 (Box-folder 25: 2)
  - Annual meeting, Tokyo, 1997 (Box-folder 25: 3)
  - Annual meeting, Washington, 1999 (Box-folder 25: 4)
  - The Trilateral Commission at 25, speeches and toasts, 1998 December (Box-folder 25: 5)
- "Managing the International System Over the Next Ten Years: Three Essays,", 1997July (Box-folder 25: 6)
- "Latin America at a Crossroads: The Challenge to the Trilateral Countries,", 1990 August (Box-folder 25: 7)
- "Special Report: Strategic Plan for Battelle,", 1979 (Box-folder 25: 8)
- "World Politics in the 1980s: A BASICS Report,", 1980 September (Box-folder 25: 9)
- "The Triangle Papers: Directions for World Trade in the Nineteen-Seventies,", 1974 June (Box-folder 26: 1)
- "The Triangle Papers: Towards a Renovated International System,", 1977 May (Box-folder 26: 2)
- "The Triangle Papers: The Crisis of International Cooperation,", 1973 October (Box-folder 26: 3)
- "The Triangle Papers: The Problem of International Consultations,", 1977 May (Box-folder 26: 4)
- The World and the School, 1965 May (Box-folder 26: 5)
- International relations, cultural interaction, 1966-1997 (Box-folder 26: 6-7)
- Correspondence, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 26: 8-10)
- Aussen Politik: German Foreign Affairs Review, Vol. 47 and 48, 1996-1997 (Box 27)
- L'Europe en Formation
  - La Grande-Bretagne et L'Europe
    - No. 95, 1968 February (Box 27)
    - No. 99, 1968 June (Box 27)
    - No. 100, 1968 July (Box 27)
  - La Tragédie Tchécoslovaque
    - No. 101-102, 1968 August-September (Box 27)
    - No. 103, 1968 October (Box 27)
  - La crise Universitaire en Europe, No. 104, 1968 November (Box 27)
  - La crise Monétaire, No. 106a, 1968 December (Box 27)
  - La crise de L'Euratom, No. 106b, 1969 January (Box 27)
  - L'Europe et L'Afrique, No. 107, 1969 February (Box 27)
  - L'avenir de l'agriculture Européenne, no. 108, 1969 March (Box 27)
  - L'Europe des régions, No. 109, 1969 April (Box 27)
  - L'Europe sans De Gaulle, No. 110, 1969 May (Box 27)
  - Le vingtiéme anniversaire du Conseil de l'Europe
    - No. 111, 1969 June (Box 27)
    - No. 112-117, 1969 July-December (Box 27)
    - No. 118-129, 1970 (Box 27)
    - No. 130, 1971 January (Box 27)
    - No. 131, 1971 February (Box 27)
  - L'ordre nouveau quarante ans aprés, No. 132, 1971 March (Box 27)
  - Le 100e anniversaire de la commune de Paris
    - No. 133, 1971 April (Box 27)
    - No. 134, 1971 May (Box 27)
    - No. 135, 1971 June (Box 27)
- Battelle publications and information, 1976-1981 (Box 27)
- The Federalist: A Political Review, Year XXXII to Year XLII, 1990-2000 (Box 28)
- Correspondence, 2001-2003 (Box-folder 29: 1-5)
- Collected material on communism, 1952-2004 (Box-folder 30: 1-3)
- Collected newspaper articles, 1970-1995 (Box-folder 30: 4)
- Council on Foreign Relations, 1975-2003 (Box-folder 30: 5)
- Council on East Asian Studies, 1979 January (Box-folder 30: 5)
- Council for International Urban Liaison, 1979-1983 (Box-folder 30: 6)
- Collected materials on international education, 1980-1998 (Box-folder 30: 7)
- Council for European Studies, 1982 (Box-folder 30: 8)
- Council for Intercultural Studies and Programs, New York, 1982 (Box-folder 30: 9)
- "Understanding International Affairs" seminar, 1986 December (Box-folder 30: 10)
- Council for International Educational Exchange, undated (Box-folder 30: 11)
- Japan and other countries, 1971-1993 (Box-folder 31: 1)
- Japan and UN (and affiliates), 1973-1974 (Box-folder 31: 2)
- Japan, foundations and philanthropy, 1974-2000 (Box-folder 31: 3-4)
- Japan, foreign policy, 1975-1993 (Box-folder 31: 5)
- Articles on totalitarianism, 1976-2003 (Box-folder 31: 6)
- Educational exchanges, 1985-2004 (Box-folder 31: 7)
- Articles on U.S. Foreign Policy, 1960-2004 (Box-folder 31: 8-13)
- Japan
  - LDCs and Development, 1974-1997 (Box-folder 32: 1)
  - External economic relations, 1975-1996 (Box-folder 32: 2-6)
  - Military and strategic, 1973-2002 (Box-folder 32: 7-12)
- "Council for a Community of Democracies- Points for Discussion,", 2004 May (Box-folder 32: 13-14)
- Note cards, Huntley's political, economic, and anthropological notes on Japan, undated (Box 33)
- An Assault on Complexity: A Battelle Monograph, 1973 April (Box-folder 34: 1)
- "Prospects for the Ford Motor Company in Europe, 1975-1985,", 1975 January (Box-folder 34: 2)
- "World Politics and World Business" seminars, lecture plan and outline, 1982 (Box-folder 34: 3)
- Correspondence, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 34: 4-7)
- "The Atlantic Council Policy Papers: Improving NATO Force Capabilities,", 1975 (Box 35)
- "The Atlantic Council Policy Papers: Harmonizing Economic Policy,", 1977 (Box 35)
- "The Atlantic Council Issues and Options: Challenges to Peace and Well-Being,", 1988 (Box 35)
- Encounter pamphlet, Alun Chalfont, "The Great Unilateralist Illusion,", undated (Box 35)
- "The New Central Asia: In Search of Stability,", 2000 October (Box 35)
- "The Atlantic Papers: The Nine and NATO,", 1974 July (Box 35)
- "The Atlantic Papers: Towards Rationalizing Allied Weapons Production,", 1976 October (Box 35)
- "BASICS Annual Review: World Politics in the 1980s,", 1980-1981 (Box 35)
- Battelle directories, reports, and information, 1974-1980 (Box 35)
- "Pour un message des peuples libres é l'ensemble de l'humanité,", 1962 May (Box 36)
- "The Free World's Aims for Humanity,", 1962 May (Box 36)
- "Atlantic Dilemma,", 1964 (Box 36)
- "The Atlantic Council Issues and Options: Challenges to Peace and Well-Being,", 1988 (Box 36)
- "The Atlantic Council Policy Papers: The Common Security Interests of Japan, the United States and NATO,", 1980 December (Box 36)
- "The Atlantic Council Policy Papers: Détente,", 1975 (Box 36)
- "The Atlantic Council Policy Papers: Strengthening Interparliamentary Consultation,", 1983 May (Box 36)
- "The Atlantic Council Policy Papers: The Teaching of Values and the Successor Generation" (Box 36)
- "Dialog Der Kontinente: Program der Atlantischen Partnerschaft,", 1964 (Box 36)
- "Un'economia per due continenti,", 1964 (Box 36)
- "Dialogue des Continents: un programme economique,", 1963 (Box 36)
- "Partnership for Progress: A Program for Transatlantic Action,", 1963 (Box 36)
- "Atlantic Studies/Etudes Atlantiques," Vol. III to V, 1966-1968 (Box 36)
- "Dialogo de los Continentes: fondo de cultura economica,", 1963 (Box 36)
- The Atlantic Community Quarterly, Vol. 21 to 24, 1983-1987 (Box 37)
- "National Forum: Toward the Bicentennial of the Constitution," Vol. LXIV, No. 4, Phi Kappa Phi Journal, 1984 (Box 37)
- "First Report of the Commission on the Bicentennial of the United States Constitution,", 1985 September (Box 37)
- "The National Interest," No. 5, 1986 (Box 37)
- "Cosmos: A Journal of Emerging Issues," Vol. 2 and 3, 1992-1993 (Box 37)
- "Freedom at Issue," No. 96, 1987 May (Box 37)
- "The Place of the United States in European Education,", 1966 (Box 37)
- "Atlantic Studies/Etudes Atlantiques:" No. 1 and 2, 1964-1965 (Box 37)
- "International Schools and their Role in the Field of International Education,", 1969 (Box 37)
- "Nordic Cooperation," brochure, 1978 (Box 38)
- "Who Does What in the Common Market,", 1982 March (Box 38)
- "Europe: A Checklist," booklet, 1972 (Box 38)
- "World Affairs Programs for 1969-1970," pamphlet, 1969 October (Box 38)
- "High School Student Programs: Students Abroad," handbook, 1968 (Box 38)
- "Summer Study, Travel and Work Programs: Students Abroad," handbook, 1968 (Box 38)
- "Semester and Academic Year Programs: Students Abroad," handbook, 1967 (Box 38)
- "Council on International Educational Exchange," pamphlet, 1967 (Box 38)
- "American Association of State Colleges and Universities," pamphlet, 1968 (Box 38)
- "One Out of Five: The State Colleges and Universities in a Time of Expanding Responsibility," brochure, 1967 (Box 38)
- Intercom Journal, 1966 July (Box 38)
- "DACOR Membership Directory,", 1972 (Box 38)
- "The Conference on North Atlantic Community," publications, 1957 September (Box 38)
- "North Atlantic Assembly: General Report on the Economics of Atlantic Security,", 1980 November (Box 38)
- The Atlantic Community Quarterly, Vol. 21, 22 and 25, 1983-1984, 1987 (Box 38)
- "International Relations: Democracy and Civic Culture," reports, 1983-1988 (Box-folder 39: 1-2)
- "International Relations: UN Affiliates and Other Global Organizations,", 1987-2002 (Box-folder 39: 3)
- Japan
  - Internal, articles, 1974-1994 (Box-folder 39: 4)
  - Institutions and individuals, articles, 1976-1997 (Box-folder 39: 5)
  - Articles and correspondence, 1981-1996 (Box-folder 39: 6)
  - Bibliography, 1971-1997 (Box-folder 39: 7-9)
- International relations
  Collected articles, reports, and correspondence.
  - Democracy and civic culture, 1974-1999 (Box-folder 40: 1-9)
  - Democracy and civic culture, 2000-2004 (Box-folder 41: 1)
  - Federalism, 1964-2002 (Box-folder 41: 2-6)
  - Global security, strategy, and geo-politics, 1974-1997 (Box-folder 41: 7)
  - Global economics, 1974-1985 (Box-folder 41: 8)
  - Economic systems, 1981-1991 (Box-folder 41: 9)
  - Individual countries, articles
    - Singapore, 1985-1998 (Box-folder 42: 1)
    - Afghanistan, 1980-1997 (Box-folder 42: 2)
    - Hong Kong, 1975-1997 (Box-folder 42: 3)
    - Korea, 1985-1998 (Box-folder 42: 4)
    - China, 1975-1979 (Box-folder 42: 5-6)
  - Far Right, 1980-2004 (Box-folder 42: 7-10)
  - New Left, 1979-2003 (Box-folder 42: 11)
  - Right Wing Totalitarianism, 1974-1986 (Box-folder 42: 12)
  - Off beat parties, 1980 (Box-folder 42: 13)
  - Neo-conservatives, 1991-1999 (Box-folder 42: 14)
  - Terrorism, 1996 (Box-folder 42: 15)
  - Federalism, community, development, 1994-2004 (Box-folder 42: 16)
  - Inflation, 1974-1981 (Box-folder 42: 17)
- The Atlantic Community Quarterly, Vol. 20, 1982 (Box 43)
- Interplay: The Magazine of International Affairs, Vol. 2 to 3, 1968-1969 (Box 43)
- Crisis Papers, booklets
  - "The Energy Crisis,", 1973 December (Box 43)
  - "The Atlantic Crisis,", 1974 April (Box 43)
  - "The Middle East and the Super Powers,", 1973 November (Box 43)
  - "Chile,", 1973 October (Box 43)
  - "The Watergate Affair,", 1973 May (Box 43)
  - "The French Election,", 1973 March (Box 43)
  - "Northern Ireland, The White Paper,", 1973 April (Box 43)
  - "How to Make the Bust Use of the 'Crisis Papers,' A Guide for Teachers,", 1973 January (Box 43)
  - "Vietnam, the End of the War,", 1973 February (Box 43)
  - "The Two Winners, Nixon and Brandt,", 1972 December (Box 43)
  - "The Uganda Refugees; A World Problem,", 1972 November (Box 43)
  - "Politics and International Sport,", 1972 October (Box 43)
  - "History in the Making," no. 26, 1972 May-July (Box 43)
  - "SALT- Signed and Sealed,", 1972 June (Box 43)
  - "Ulster at War,", 1971 December (Box 43)
  - "Nixon Abroad: The New Diplomacy,", 1972 May (Box 43)
  - "History in the Making,", 1971 January-April (Box 43)
  - "Bangla Desh: War as an Instrument of Policy,", 1972 January (Box 43)
  - "The Dollar in Europe,", 1971 May (Box 43)
  - "6+4=10; The Wider Europe,", 1971 July (Box 43)
  - "Inflation,", 1970 November (Box 43)
  - "Community Violence: The Challenge of the Urban Guerrilla,", 1971 April (Box 43)
  - "Rolls-Royce and Lockheed: Partners in Adversity,", 1971 March (Box 43)
  - "The Commonwealth: What Is It Worth?,", 1971 February (Box 43)
  - "Hijacking,", 1970 September (Box 43)
  - "The Two Germanys: East Meets West,", 1970 May (Box 43)
  - "The Domino Theory: Laos and Cambodia,", 1970 April (Box 43)
  - "The Middle East: The Permanent Crisis,", 1969 April (Box 43)
  - "The Moscow Conference: The International Communist Movement, Yesterday, Today, and Tomorrow,", 1969 July (Box 43)
  - "The Nigerian Civil War: The Defeat of Biafra,", 1970 January (Box 43)
  - "The November Crisis: The Franc and the Mark,", 1968 December (Box 43)
  - "Northern Ireland,", 1969 October (Box 43)
  - "The State of Europe,", 1974 July (Box 43)
- "Interdisciplinary Studies in Secondary Schools: A Report from the Atlantic Information Centre for Teachers,", 1968 September (Box 43)
- "Teaching about the American Impact on Europe: A Report from the Atlantic Information Centre for Teachers,", 1969 November (Box 43)
- "Learning about International Institutions in Secondary Schools: A Report from the Atlantic Information Centre for Teachers,", 1970 September (Box 43)
- "National Stereotypes- An Educational Challenge: A Report from the Atlantic Information Centre for Teachers" (Box 43)
- The Atlantic Community Quarterly, Vol. 18 to 21, 1980-1983 (Box 44)
- Personal day planners and diaries, 1967-1978 (Box 44)
- The Federalist Debate: Papers for Federalists in Europe and the World, Year XIII, No. 2, 2000 (Box 45)
- The Federalist Debate: Papers for Federalists in Europe and the World, Year XIV, No. 1, 2001 (Box 45)
- The Atlantic Community Quarterly, Vol. 25 to 26, 1987-1988 (Box 45)
- Foreign Affairs, Vol. 64 to 65, 1985-1987 (Box 45)
- Correspondence, 1995-1997 (Box-folder 46: 1-3)
- Individual countries
  - China, 1980-2004 (Box-folder 46: 4-7)
  - Pakistan, 1990-2002 (Box-folder 46: 8)
- Correspondence, Ray Gastil, 1989-1991 (Box-folder 47: 1)
- Correspondence, Dan Evans, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 47: 2)
- Ryszard Paszkowkski/Kulinski case, 1997-1998 (Box-folder 47: 3-4)
- Correspondence
  - Walter Raymond, 1985-1992 (Box-folder 47: 5)
  - Steven Rosenberg, 1994 (Box-folder 47: 6)
  - Istvan Szent-Miklosy, 1974, 1987-1995 (Box-folder 47: 7)
  - Itaru Umezu, 1992 (Box-folder 47: 8)
  - Don Vollmer and Pacific Northwest Advisors, 1990-1997 (Box-folder 47: 9-10)
- Anne Huntley file, 1995 October (Box-folder 48: 1)
- Chris Kane file, 1991-1995 (Box-folder 48: 2)
- The Federalist: A Political Review; Year XXVI to XXX, 1984-1988 (Box-folder 48: 3-14)
- Atlantic-Pacific Club, Seattle and Jean Francois-Poncet luncheon, 1971-1982 (Box-folder 49: 1--3)
- Correspondence
  - General correspondence, 1989-1996 (Box-folder 49: 4-7)
  - Ackerman, Martin, 1987-1998 (Box-folder 49: 8)
  - Allen, Dave, 1990 (Box-folder 49: 9)
  - Clink, Ronald, 1993-1997 (Box-folder 49: 10)
  - Cowger, Mary, 1977-1986 (Box-folder 49: 11)
  - Faulkner, Lyman, 1986-1993 (Box-folder 49: 12)
  - Hansen, Don, 1990-1992 (Box-folder 49: 13)
- Non-government institutions
  Includes correspondence, reports, and brochures.
  - Atlantic Council, Successor Generation Working Group, 1978-1983 (Box-folder 50: 1-6)
  - The Aspen Institute Berlin, 1977-1991 (Box-folder 51: 1)
  - The Asia Society, 1982 (Box-folder 51: 2)
  - The Atlantic Committee of Piedmont, 1992 (Box-folder 51: 3)
  - Atlantic Council of Canada, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 51: 4)
  - Atlantic Council of the UK, 2002 (Box-folder 51: 5)
  - Atlantic Council of the US, 1974-2000 (Box-folder 51: 6-10)
  - American Friends of Turkey, 1987-1989 (Box-folder 52: 1)
  - American Heritage Association, 1982 (Box-folder 52: 2)
  - American Institute for Contemporary German Studies, 1987 (Box-folder 52: 3)
  - American Movement for World Government, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 52: 4)
  - American-Scandinavian Foundation, 1983 (Box-folder 52: 5)
  - Association for International Practical Training, 1982-1992 (Box-folder 52: 6)
  - Association Internationale Pour L'étude de L'économie de L'Assurance, 1974-1978 (Box-folder 52: 7)
  - AFS International/Intercultural Programs, 1982 (Box-folder 52: 8)
  - Association to Unite the Democracies, 1986-2003 (Box-folder 52: 9)
  - Atlantic Committee, Netherlands
    - General, 1980-1982 (Box-folder 52: 10)
    - Lexicon: Politiek-Militair-Strategische Termen, 1979 (Box-folder 52: 11)
    - "Atlantisch Perspectief," No. 1, 1982 (Box-folder 52: 12)
    - "Atlantisch Perspectief," No. 2, 1982 (Box-folder 52: 13)
    - "Atlantisch Perspectief," No. 4, 1982 (Box-folder 52: 14)
    - "Atlantische Studie," No. 2, 1980 January (Box-folder 52: 15)
    - "Atlantische Studie," No. 3, 1980 August (Box-folder 52: 16)
    - "Atlantische Studie," No. 4, 1981 June (Box-folder 52: 17)
  - Atlantic Association of Young Political Leaders, 1977 (Box-folder 52: 18)
  - Atlantik Bruecke e.V., 1975-2000 (Box-folder 52: 19)
  - AMNESTY International, 1981-1991 (Box-folder 52: 20)
  - Anglo-German Foundation Industrial Society, 1981-1986 (Box-folder 52: 21)
  - Association of Professional Schools of International Affairs (APSIA), undated (Box-folder 52: 22)
  - Arbeitskreis Deutsch-Französiche Gesellschaften e.V., 1982-1983 (Box-folder 52: 23)
  - The Asia Foundation, 1978-1983 (Box-folder 52: 24)
  - American Foreign Service Association, undated (Box-folder 52: 25)
  - American University, Washington D.C., undated (Box-folder 52: 26)
  - American Council on Germany, 1979-1982 (Box-folder 52: 27)
  - The Aspen Institute, 1979-1991 (Box-folder 53: 1)
  - American Political Foundation, 1979-1982 (Box-folder 53: 2)
  - Academy of Independent Scholars, 1982-1984 (Box-folder 53: 3)
  - Academy of Political Science, undated (Box-folder 53: 4)
  - General, 1973-1985 (Box-folder 53: 5)
  - General, 1973-1985 (Box-folder 53: 6)
  - American-European Community Association, 1981-1987 (Box-folder 53: 7-8)
  - The Atlantic Institute, correspondence, 1957-1958 (Box-folder 54: 1-3)
  - The Atlantic Institute, 1957-2002 (Box-folder 54: 4)
  - Atlantic Conferences (Bruges, London, Paris), 1957-2002 (Box-folder 54: 5-6)
  - American Council for Young Political Leaders, 1977-1982 (Box-folder 54: 7)
  - American Cultural Exchange, 1977-1996 (Box-folder 54: 8)
  - American Enterprise Institute, 1977-1982 (Box-folder 54: 9)
  - Committee on Atlantic Studies, 1963-1965 (Box-folder 55: 1)
  - Committee on Atlantic Studies, grant requests, 1965 (Box-folder 55: 2)
  - Atlantic Treaty Assembly, 1971, 1980-1984 (Box-folder 55: 3-4)
  - British Council of the European Movement, European Luncheon Club, 1970 (Box-folder 55: 5)
  - Business International Corporation, 1969 (Box-folder 55: 6)
  - Cate Conference, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 55: 7)